Sanjar Adilov | Curriculum Vitae

ML Software Engineer, BSc in Applied Math and Computer Science. Broadly interested in machine learning, esp. deep learning and its applications in natural language processing. Working on full-stack research and development of conversational AI experiences.

Employment

Data ScientistAug 2022 - PresentAlif TechTashkent, Uzbekistan

- o Modeling, development & operationalization of a task-oriented, closed-domain conversational Al assistant.
- o Little bit of backend and/or modeling for document OCR, credit scoring, transaction fraud monitoring.

Research Engineer II Jan 2021 – Aug 2022

Romanovsky Institute of Mathematics, Academy of Sciences of Uzbekistan

Tashkent, Uzbekistan

Adapting deep learning for drug design by building a unified framework for downstream generative and supervised molecular tasks via large-scale causal transformers (see, e.g., smiles-gpt).

Research Assistant Jan 2019 – Dec 2020

Romanovsky Institute of Mathematics, Academy of Sciences of Uzbekistan

Tashkent, Uzbekistan

- o Single-/multi-output classification of high-dimensional molecular data (see, e.g., sparse-cheml).
- o Improvement of SOTA generative molecular models (see, e.g., moleculegen).
- o Survival analysis of patients with COVID-19 in Uzbekistan.

Research Engineer I Sep 2018 – Dec 2018

Romanovsky Institute of Mathematics, Academy of Sciences of Uzbekistan

Tashkent, Uzbekistan

ML for low-data QSPR/QSAR modeling using graph neural networks (see, e.g., nitrocom-learning).

Intern Jun 2017 – Aug 2018

Misc. Tashkent, Uzbekistan

Several internships. Mostly bash scripting and basic frontend & backend development.

Education

BSc in Applied Mathematics and Computer Science

Sep 2014 - Jun 2018

Lomonosov Moscow State University in Tashkent

Tashkent, Uzbekistan

- o Main coursework include pure & applied math, intelligent systems, and scientific computing.
- o Research and thesis on graph theory (coloring and planarity testing).
- o Volunteer instructor at Math and Programming Club for prospective students.
- o ACM-ICPC NEERC contestant.

Publications

Adilov, Sanjar (2021): Generative Pre-Training from Molecules. ChemRxiv. Preprint.

https://doi.org/10.33774/chemrxiv-2021-5fwjd

S.Sh. Adilov. An upper bound for the chromatic number of graphs with given thickness and girth. In *Intelligent systems. Theory and applications*, volume 22, issue 3, 2018.

And more in my Google Scholar: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=NzU11nAAAAAJ

Skills

- o Programming Languages: Python &, Bash, SQL, LATEX, C, R.
- o Tools: [DS] PyTorch 4, Scikit-Learn, Pandas, etc.; [MLE] DVC, MLFlow; [SE] Git, Sanic, Docker, K8S.
- Concepts & Practices: Scientific Research, CI/CD, Scrum, OSSD.

Misc.

- o **Community Service**: Mentoring in hackathons (one has eventually become an integral part of our credit scoring ecosystem); public presentations on DL life cycle, foundational models.
- o **Side Projects**: scikit-fallback: machine learning w/ rejections (on Medium and Github).
- o Hobbies: Guitars, music, books, movies, swimming.